本期Primal Space视频由Skillshare赞助
This episode of Primal Space is supported by Skillshare,
一个可以在线学习任何东西的社区
an online learning community where you can learn just about anything!
点击下方链接获取两个月的免费试用
Sign up using the link below to get your first 2 months for free.
2015年12月21日 太空叉的猎鹰九号火箭首次完成陆地着陆 创造了历史
On the 21st of December 2015, SpaceX made history by landing their first Falcon 9 booster back on land.
在多年的研发与测试后
After years of development and testing,
太空叉离大幅降低航天发射成本的目标更近了一步
SpaceX were one step closer to dramatically reducing the cost of spaceflight.
直到目前 有超过45枚一级火箭成功着陆 其中超过一半是复用的
Since then, over 45 boosters have been landed with over half of them being reused.
那么猎鹰九号可以重复使用多少次？
But how many times can a Falcon 9 be reused?
复用发射之前的翻新又需要做些什么？
And what does it take to refurbish each booster between flights?
本期视频 我们将了解太空叉如何提高猎鹰九号的可复用性
In this video, we're going to look at how SpaceX upgraded the Falcon 9 to be more reusable,
我们还将了解猎鹰九号在翻新过程中发生了什么
we're also going to look at what goes into refurbishing the Falcon 9
以及其最终将如何被Starship取代
and how it will eventually be replaced by Starship.
2018年4月 太空叉发射了全新改进后的猎鹰九号"Block5"
In April 2018, SpaceX launched the new and improved "Block 5" Falcon 9.
这个全新的版本对发动机隔热罩、格栅舵、着陆腿等进行了大量升级
This new version brought a number of upgrades to the engine heat shield, grid fins and landing legs,
旨在降低其翻新的工作量
with an aim to reduce the amount of refurbishment
并最大化每枚一级火箭的飞行次数
and maximize the number of flights per booster.
尽管此次升级减少了大量的翻新需求
Although this upgrade cut out the need for a lot of refurbishment,
但每枚一级平均翻新时间也只是从356天降低到107天
the average turnaround time for a booster has only dropped from 356 days to 107,
最快记录是72天
with the quickest turnaround time being 72 days.
与之相比的航天飞机 在1985年就创造了更快的55天复用记录
The Space Shuttle on the other hand achieved a record of just 55 days between flights back in 1985,
而当时正常的翻新时间也少于100天
with regular refurbishment times of less than 100 days.
然而在挑战者号灾难之后 安全标准提升
However, after the Challenger disaster, the safety standards increased
为翻新带来了额外的压力
and this put extra pressure on refurbishment.
翻新过程变成了又庞大又昂贵的工程
The process became an enormously expensive task,
需要超过9000人才能让航天飞机重新上天
requiring over 9,000 employees to make the Shuttle ready for flight.
太空叉想要达到24小时翻新的目标
With SpaceX aiming to achieve a refurbishment time of just 24 hours,
就要做到像民航那样的周转
they will need to match the turnaround process of airliners,
在每次发射之间只进行快速检查
with each rocket only needing a quick inspection between flights.
当一级火箭返回 或着陆或着船
When the first stage booster returns to Earth either by land or by sea,
它都会放上卡车送回太空叉的机库
it's lifted onto a trailer and transported back to the SpaceX hangar.
这会花上很多天 因为四个着陆腿需要挨个手动拆卸下来
This can take multiple days to complete since each of the four landing legs need to be removed manually.
虽然它们设计是可快速收回的 但太空叉只完成过两次
Although they are designed to be quickly retracted, SpaceX have only been able to do this on two occasions.
一级火箭回到机库后 翻新工作就开始了
Once the booster is back in the hangar, the refurbishment process begins
每台发动机都会进行大量严格测试来保证每个零件还能上天
with each engine going through a number of rigorous tests to make sure that every component is ready for flight.
根据马一龙所说 每台梅林发动机可以在不进行大修的情况下飞行1000次
According to Musk, each Merlin engine could perform up to 1000 flights without major refurbishment.
格栅舵液压系统——去年着陆失效过一次——也要检查是否有泄露
The hydraulic grid fin system—which failed during a landing last year—must also be checked for any leaks.
燃料罐和加压罐要进行一系列超声波探伤
The fuel tanks and pressure vessels go through a series of ultrasonic tests
防止在火箭加压后其中的微小裂纹可能导致的失败
to check for tiny cracks that could lead to a failure once the rocket is pressurized for flight.
一级火箭探查工作完成后
Once the booster has passed the inspection process,
它会用九台发动机进行静态点火 之后再安装载荷
it performs a static fire test with all 9 engines, before being attached to the payload.
之后太空叉冒险进行更多次复用发射时 还要重新进行所有这些检查工作
At the moment, all of these checks still need to be completed
as they venture into the unknown territory of multiple reuses.
每次发射都能让它们更加了解每枚一级火箭能飞多少次
Each mission will give them more knowledge on how many flights each booster can perform,
随着时间的推移 翻新流程应该会更加简化
and over time, the refurbishment process should become more refined.
迄今为止有三发猎鹰九号的一级完成了三次发射
So far, there are three Falcon 9 boosters that have each completed triple launches.
太空叉当前库存约有八枚猎鹰九号一级火箭
SpaceX currently has around eight Falcon 9 boosters in their fleet,
而太空叉的最终目标是达到20
but eventually they aim to grow that number to 20.
虽然猎鹰九号理论上可以在少量翻新情况下飞行100次
Although the Falcon 9 could theoretically fly up to 100 times with minimal refurbishment,
但每枚一级火箭在未来十年也只能发射大约30次
each booster is only expected to perform a total of around 30 flights over the next decade.
然而 太空叉还在研发更加强大 完全可复用的火箭
However, with SpaceX working on a much more powerful and fully reusable rocket,
可以逼得自家猎鹰九号更快下岗
the Falcon 9 could become obsolete much sooner than expected.
太空叉正在德州和佛州建造Starship的原型火箭
SpaceX is currently building the first prototypes of their "Starship" rocket in Texas and Florida.
客户也已经开始排队 打算2021年发射第一发商业载荷
And with customers already lined up, they aim to launch their first commercial payload in 2021.
太空叉也不仅仅想用Starship飞往火星或发射商业载荷
Not only will SpaceX use Starship for Mars and commercial satellite missions,
他们还想将Starship用于地球旅行
they also want to use Starship for travel here on Earth,
让世界任意两点间的飞行只需不到一小时
providing flights to anywhere in the world in well under an hour.
与猎鹰九号不同的是 Starship设计完全可复用
Unlike the Falcon 9, Starship is designed to be fully reusable
目标是不需要任何大修即可完成一千次飞行
with an aim to complete thousands of flights before any major refurbishment is needed.
如果太空叉的Starship真成了 那它将能完全取代猎鹰九号
If SpaceX can get Starship up and running, it could replace the Falcon 9 all together
因为Starship可以发射更重的载荷 且费用更低
since it would be capable of launching much heavier payloads for a fraction of the cost.
在几年后 太空叉将公开招募数千名新员工投入Starship中去
Over the next few years, SpaceX will be hiring thousands of new employees to work on Starship.
当开始招募的时候 马一龙曾承诺他不在意大学学位
When it comes to hiring, Elon Musk has admitted that he doesn't care about college degrees.
“甚至不需要有大学学位”
there's no need even to have a college degree
实际上 在太空叉的早期
In fact, in the early days of SpaceX,
马一龙也是通过自己看书 和工厂里的人聊天学会的火箭知识
Elon taught himself rocket science by reading books and talking to people in the industry.
如今我们有了B站这个学习网站和各种像Skillshare的网络课程
Nowadays we are surrounded by amazing tools like YouTube tutorials and online classes like Skillshare,
我们足不出户就能学习各种知识和技能了
that allow us to learn about any topic or skill without having to leave the house!
Skillshare是一款拥有上千门课程的在线学习社区
Skillshare is an online learning community with thousands of classes.
从让你自己开公司的创业技能
From entrepreneurial skills that help you grow your own business,
到Paul Gana教你天梯摄影学的创造性技能
to creative skills like this astrophotography lesson from Paul Gana,
(可以教你如何拍摄震撼的星空照片)
which shows you how to capture stunning images of the stars at night.
想要在Skillshare上有每节课程无限次观看权限
For unlimited access to every single course on Skillshare,
需要的高级会员每月不到10美元
a premium membership costs less than 10 dollars a month
如果点击下方链接注册 则能领取两月免费试用
and if you sign up using the link in the description, you can get the first two months for free!
超过两千门课程 总有一款适合你
With over 20,000 classes just a click away, it's easy to find the course that's right for you.
无论你是想为了你梦想的职业而学习新技能
So whether you want to learn a new skill that leads into your dream career,
或者只是想学些技能让自己更有生产力
or you just want to learn some life hacks to be more productive,
Skillshare都非常适合你
Skillshare is the perfect place to do it.
感谢观看本期视频 我们下期见
Thank you very much for watching and I'll see you in the next video!